Harvard CfA 60 Garden St, Cambridge, MA 02144 Phone: (267) 257-3027 rahuldave@gmail.comu http://rahuldave.nareau.com

RAHUL DAVE

Goals

Teaching: To combine computation and science in service of communicating concepts to students by reducing them to their essence. To experiment with innovative techniques from software development and online learning to enhance both the development of both conceptual and implementation skills.

Research: To develop fast computational techniques for automatic analysis of astronomical objects. To optimize information retrieval for scientists using past searching history, and based on the stage of their career and their specific interests. INFERENCE.

Appointments

Harvard University

2013-Present. Educator and TA: Harvard University SEAS and Library

2010–Present. Computational Scientist: Astrophysical Data Systems (ADS) at the Center for Astrophysics (CfA).

2007–2009. Computational Scientist: Initiative in Innovative Computing (IIC).

University of Pennsylvania

2002–2006. Researcher, Taiwan America Occultation Survey (TAOS). 1998–2002. Associate Director, Eniac 2000 and Liniac Supercomputing Projects.

Education

University of Pennsylvania

2002. Ph.D, Physics. Dissertation: Missing energy in the universe: Quintessence and the microwave background.

St. Xaviers College, University of Bombay

1993. B.S. Physics (Honors.)

Projects and Presentations

2005. "The Political Economy of Presumed Consent." University of California, Los Angeles. May.

2005. "Last Best Gifts: Altruism and the Market for Human Organs." University of California, Berkeley. April.

2005. "Cadaveric Organ Procurement and Presumed Consent Laws." De-Paul Law Review & Health Law Institute Symposium on *Precious Commodities: The Supply and Demand of Body Parts.* Chicago. March.

- 2005. "Last Best Gifts: Altruism and the Market for Human Organs." University of Washington. February.
- 2004. "The Institutional Context of Organ Procurement." Indiana University—Purdue University, Indianapolis. November.
- 2004. "The Political Economy of Presumed Consent." SPT Program, Australian National University, RSSS. July.
- 2004. "Organ Procurement in the United States." National University of Ireland at Maynooth. April.
- 2004. "The Institutional Context of Organ Procurement." Indiana University—Purdue University, Indianapolis. November.
- 2004. "The Political Economy of Presumed Consent." SPT Program, Australian National University, RSSS. July.
- 2004. "Organ Procurement in the United States." National University of Ireland at Maynooth. April.

Selected Publications

- Marion Fourcade and Kieran Healy. 2007. "Moral Views of Market Society." Annual Review of Sociology 33: 285–311.
- Kieran Healy. 2006. "Do Presumed Consent Laws Raise Organ Procurement Rates?" DePaul Law Review 55: 1017–1043.
- Kieran Healy. 2004. "Altruism as an Organizational Problem: The Case of Organ Procurement." American Sociological Review 69: 387–404.
- Kieran Healy. 2002. "Digital Technology and Cultural Goods." *Journal of Political Philosophy* 10: 478–500.
- Kieran Healy. 2002. "What's New for Culture in the New Economy?" Journal of Arts Management, Law and Society 32: 86–103.
- Kieran Healy. 2000. "Embedded Altruism: Blood Collection Regimes and the European Union's Donor Population." American Journal of Sociology 105: 1633–1657.
- Kieran Healy. 1999. "The Emergence of HIV in the U.S. Blood Supply: Organizations, Obligations and the Management of Uncertainty." *Theory and Society* 28: 529–558.
- Bruce Western and Kieran Healy. 1999. "Explaining the OECD Wage Slowdown: Recession or Labor Decline?" European Sociological Review 15: 233–249.
- Kieran Healy. 1998. "Conceptualising Constraint: Mouzelis, Archer and the concept of social structure." Sociology 32: 509–522.

Skills (by topic)

Data Science: Machine Learning, Statistics, Numerical Programming, Databases.

Computing: parallel, functional, architecture, scientific, simulation, multiagent

Programming Languages: python, matlab, R, julia, javascript, coffeescript, scheme/clojure, java, C, C++, fortran

Software: postgresql, redis, mongodb, node.js, flask, django, AWS, MPI, Hadoop, Netlogo, RDF

Architecture: semantic web, large database, web, cluster

Science: Cosmology, Astronomy, Physics, Economics

Other Avid Skier, rock climber and hiker